Let's jump in and learn about
the multi head attention mechanism.
The notation gets a little
bit complicated, but
the thing to keep in mind is basically
just a big for-loop over the self
attention mechanism that you
learned about in the last video.
Let's take a look each time you
calculate self attention for
a sequence is called a head.
And thus the name multi head attention
refers to if you do what you saw in
the last video, but a bunch of times
let's walk through how this works.
Remember that you got the vectors Q K and
V for
each of the input terms by multiplying
them by a few matrices, W Q W K and W V.
With multi head attention,
you take that same set of query key and
value vectors as inputs.
So the q, k, v values written down here
and calculate multiple self attentions.
So the first of these, you multiply the k,
q, v matrices with weight matrices,
w one q, w one k and w one v.
And so these three values give
you a new set of query key and
value vectors for the first words.
And you do the same thing for
each of the other words.
For the sake of intuition, you might
find it useful to think of w one q,
w one k and
w one v as being learned to help ask and
answer the question,
what's happening there?
And so this is just more or
less the self attention
example that we walked through
earlier in the previous video.
After finishing you may think,
we have w q, w one q, w one k,
w one v, I learn to help you ask and
answer the question, what's happening?
And so with this computation, the word
visite gives the best answer to
what's happening, which is why
I've highlighted with this blue
arrow over here to represent that
the inner product between the key for
l'Afrique has the highest value
with the query for visite,
which is the first of
the questions we'll get to ask.
So this is how you get
the representation for l'Afrique and
you do the same for Jane, visite and
the other words en septembre.
So you end up with five vectors to
represent the five words in the sequence.
So this is a computation you carry out for
the first of the several heads
you use in multi head attention.
And so you would step through exactly the
same calculation that we had just now for
l'Afrique and for the other words and
end up with the same attention values,
a one through a five that we
had in the previous video.
But now we're going to do this
not once but a handful of times.
So that rather than having one head,
we may now have eight heads,
which just means performing this
whole calculation maybe eight times.
And so so far, we've computed this
quantity of attention with the first
head indicated by the subsequent
one in these matrices.
And the attention equation is just this,
which you had previously seen
in the last video as well.
Now, let's do this computation
with the second head.
The second head will have
a new set of matrices.
I'm going to write WQ two, WK two and
WV two that allows this
mechanism to ask and
answer a second question.
So the first question
was what's happening?
Maybe the second question is
when is something happening?
And so instead of having W
one here in the general case,
we will have here Wi and
I've now stacked up the second head
behind the first one was
the second one shown in red.
So you repeat a computation that's
exactly the same as the first one but
with this new set of matrices instead.
And you end up with in this case maybe
the inner product between the september
key and the l'Afrique query will
have the highest inner product.
So I'm going to highlight this red arrow
to indicate that the value for september
will play a large role in this second
part of the representation for l'Afrique.
Maybe the third question
we now want to ask
as represented by W Q three, W K three and
WV three is who,
who has something to do with Africa?
And in this case when you do
this computation the third time,
maybe the inner product
between Jane's key vector and
the l'Afrique query vector
will be highest and
self highlighted this black arrow here.
So that Jane's value will
have the greatest weight
in this representation which
I've now stacked on at the back.
In the literature,
the number of heads is usually
represented by the lower case letter H.
And so H is equal to the number of heads.
And you can think of each of these
heads as a different feature.
And when you pass these features to a new
network you can calculate a very rich
representation of the sentence.
Calculating these computations for
the three heads or the eight heads or
whatever the number,
the concatenation of these three values or
A values is used to compute the output
of the multi headed attention.
And so the final value is
the concatenation of all of these H heads.
And then finally multiplied by a matrix W.
Now one more detail that's worth keeping
in mind is that in the description
of multi head attention, I described
computing these different values for
the different heads as if you
would do them in a big for-loop.
And conceptually it's okay
to think of it like that.
But in practice you can actually compute
these different heads' values in
parallel because no one has value
depends on the value of any other head.
So in terms of how this is implemented,
you can actually compute all the heads
in parallel instead of sequentially.
And then concatenate
them multiply by W zero.
And there's your multi headed attention.
Now, there's a lot going on on the slide.
Thanks for sticking with me all
the way to the end of this video.
In the next video,
I'm going to use a simplified icon.
We're going to use this
little diagram here to denote
this multi head computation.
So it takes as input matrices Q, K and V.
So these values down here and
outputs this value up here.
So in the next video, when we put this
into the full transformer network,
I'm going to use this little
picture to denote all of
these computations denoted on the slide.
So, congratulations.
In the last video you
learned about self attention.
And by doing that multiple times, you
now understand the multi head attention
mechanism, which lets you ask multiple
questions for every single word and
learn a much richer,
much better representation for every word.
Let's now put all this together
to build the transformer network.
Let's go to the next video to see that.